<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Work | coderjoe.net]]></title>
  <link href="http://coderjoe.net/categories/work/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://coderjoe.net/"/>
  <updated>2012-07-27T15:37:24-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://coderjoe.net/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Joe "coderjoe" Bauser]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Oracle Core Dump Grapher]]></title>
    <link href="http://coderjoe.net/archive/2008/03/20/oracle-core-dump-grapher/"/>
    <updated>2008-03-20T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://coderjoe.net/archive/2008/03/20/oracle-core-dump-grapher</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Anyone who has ever spent any significant amount of time working with an Oracle database has probably seen a ORA-600 or ORA-07445 "exception encountered: core dump" trace file.</p>

<p>Unfortunately, when you come across an Oracle core dump you can't do much more than send the dump to Oracle and hope the issue is already resolved in a newer version, or that a patch is available for your current version.</p>

<p>This process usually consists of three steps:</p>

<ol>
<li>Collect the trace files related to the issue.</li>
<li>Open a Service Request on Oracle's Metalink site.</li>
<li>Wait for a response</li>
</ol>


<p><em>If you're lucky</em>, the first step is an easy one.</p>

<p><em>If you're lucky</em> you caught the first occurrence of the core dump and only need to shoot off a single trace file to the guys at Oracle.</p>

<p>On the other hand, if you're not lucky, you might be handed 50-60 trace files spanning multiple weeks and be asked to sort them by distinct issue for reporting to Oracle.</p>

<p>I'm <strong>not</strong> lucky.</p>

<p>Sorting the trace files is a long process which involves searching the trace file for the dump, researching the issue on Metalink, finding similar issues on Metalink, and then sorting the trace files by those issues.</p>

<p>Two trace files into the process I knew there had to be a better way. Well, what better way to organize trace files than by the stack trace that generated the dump?</p>

<p>From that idea TraceFileGrapher was born. The TraceFileGrapher takes as input a directory of trace files, and creates a graph representing the call stacks of all of the trace files resulting in core dumps. The graph is then saved as any <a href="http://www.graphviz.org" title="Graphviz: The opensource graph vizualisation package.">Graphviz</a> compatible format of your choosing.</p>

<p>The graphs themselves are simple. The starting nodes of the graph are colored green. The ending nodes are colored red. For a stack trace graph, the end nodes are the names of the trace files in which the core dump appeared. For a PL/SQL Call stack graph, the end nodes are the final PL/SQL function or procedure call name.</p>

<p>Example Graphs</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="/images/posts/2008/03/example-stack-graph.png" title="Oracle Core Dump Stack Graph">Oracle Core Dump Stack Graph</a></li>
<li><a href="/images/posts/2008/03/example-noloop-stack-graph.png" title="Oracle Core Dump Stack Graph without loops">Oracle Core Dump Stack Graph without loops</a></li>
<li><a href="/images/posts/2008/03/example-plsql-graph.png" title="PL/SQL Call Stack Graph">PL/SQL Call Stack Graph</a></li>
<li><a href="/images/posts/2008/03/example-noloop-plsql-graph.png" title="PL/SQL Call Stack Graph without loops">PL/SQL Call Stack Graph without loops</a></li>
</ul>


<p>In addition to graphing core dump stack traces, TraceFileGrapher can graph PL/SQL Call Stacks as well.</p>

<p>The TraceFileGrapher requires <a href="http://www.perl.org" title="The offical Perl webpage.">Perl</a>, the <a href="http://search.cpan.org/~tels/Graph-Easy/" title="The Graph::Easy CPAN module for creating graphs in Perl.">Graph::Easy</a> Perl module, and the <a href="http://www.graphviz.org" title="Graphviz: The open source graph visualization project.">Graphviz</a> open source graph visualization software.</p>

<p>Get the TraceFileGrapher <a href="/images/posts/2008/03/tracefilegrapher-0.1.tar.gz" title="TraceFileGrapher-0.1.tar.gz">here</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[You've won a new Job!]]></title>
    <link href="http://coderjoe.net/archive/2007/07/09/youve-won-a-new-job/"/>
    <updated>2007-07-09T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://coderjoe.net/archive/2007/07/09/youve-won-a-new-job</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I'm excited to announce that I've officially been selected for, and have started working as a Software Engineer, Associate, position at <a href="http://www.paetec.com" title="The Paetec Communications website.">Paetec Communication's</a> Software Division <a href="http://www.pinnsoft.com/" title="Pinnacle's website.">Pinnacle</a>.</p>

<p>I will return to work with my colleagues from my first and second co-op blocks. I'm happy to be back with everybody and I'll keep those who care posted on my progress and exciting adventures in Pinnacle land!</p>

<p>For those of you who are interested in tracking my job progress feel free to click my <a href="http://www.linkedin.com/in/josephbauser" title="My LinkedIn profile.">profile link</a> for the corporate social networking tool <a href="http://www.linkedin.com" title="LinkedIn business social networking.">LinkedIn</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
